blogs.it 2016-03-14

# blog.co.uk - Privacy Policy

### blog.de Privacy Notice

Protection of our users' personal data is very important to us. Users can expect us to handle their data as carefully and discretely as possible and to provide a high degree of data security. It goes without saying that we comply with the regulations of the applicable data protection legislation, and we will collect and process our users' personal data only to the extent described in the present privacy notice.

By clicking the corresponding checkbox when registering for our service, users grant us permission to collect, process, and use their personal data to the extent specified within the scope of the data processing processes described below.

**A user may, of course, revoke this consent at any time.** Revocation can be sent to us – Populis GmbH, c/o Kowert, Schwanke und Von Schwerin, Spichernstraße 2, 10777 Berlin – in writing. An e-mail sent to our customer service at support@blog.de is also sufficient. Users can also request written or electronic information regarding stored personal data by writing to this address.

  * #### **§1.** Purpose of Data Collection and Use of Data

Collecting and storing your data allows us to offer our users a user-friendly, efficient and safe Internet service. We use the personal data we have collected and processed in order to submit information to third parties within the Community, to send the newsletter as well as to implement the agreements concluded between ourselves and users regarding the use of our platform (cf. our General Conditions of Business and Use) or any further agreements. In other respects, our general data-processing activities serve to improve our services and the security level at which they are offered, but in this case we use no personal data. This type of processing is handled anonymously or with pseudonyms.

  * #### **§2.** Manner and Scope of Collection and Processing

    * #### **a)** Inventory Data

We collect and process personal data when a user registers with us and opens a user account, and, once he has opened such an account, makes use of our service. When a user account is opened, we first ask users to provide only the following data (hereinafter referred to as “inventory data”):

      * an e-mail address,
      * a user name and password selected by the user (this password is encrypted and at no time visible in clear text),
      * the user's gender,
      * date of birth, and
      * the town/city and country of the user's residence.

Users also have the option of giving their first and last names. For users choosing this option, first and last names become part of the inventory data record.

Depending on type of payment, fee-based service packages involve certain additional data (e.g. bank account information). Furthermore, a user can also broaden his user profile by providing additional data. Such additional data also becomes part of the inventory data.

We need the inventory data to manage the user accounts of our users; storing this data also allows us to reach our users if problems arise. The data is also necessary for us to implement the agreement regarding the use of our platform as well as any further agreements.

Our registered users receive an electronic newsletter sent to their e-mail address. These newsletters, which are published at reasonable intervals, contain editorial information involving our offers, topical advertising and similar material. Users may cancel receipt of the newsletter at any time.

    * ####  **b)** Utilisation Data / Utilisation Profiles / Cookies

Generally, Internet users can visit our web pages at any time without providing any personal data. However, we do set up a so-called utilisation profile under a pseudonym whenever our websites are visited by registered users or other Internet users.

      * **aa)**

When users register with us, we store their computers' IP addresses in order to protect ourselves against abuse and fraud. For the same reason, we also temporarily store the IP addresses of all registered and other users of our service when they visit our website. By accepting the present privacy notice, a user consents to this data collection and storage.

      * **bb)**

Further, we gather and store anonymised data for marketing and optimisation purposes. For instance, this might include data regarding the web page from which a user has accessed our service, the name of the user's Internet Service Provider, which web pages the user has visited within our Internet offer as well as the date and duration of the visit. These already anonymised data are then used to draw up utilisation profiles that are stored under pseudonyms. Cookies may also be used in this regard (cf. sec. 2 b) dd) and ee) below).

At no time is this data linked with other data regarding the identity of the person behind the pseudonym. This means, for example, that we do not store a particular user's utilisation patterns, but only that there is an indefinite user with this utilisation pattern. No data is stored that might allow conclusions to be drawn, for instance, regarding a user's personal click and/or read patterns.

      * **cc)**

Beyond the utilisation profiles described in sec. 2 b) bb), we also reserve the option of setting up a function through which our users can recognise what other users have recently visited their pages (by disclosing user names). To make such a function available, we would have to set up and store restricted utilisation profiles in non-anonymised form. By accepting the present privacy notice, users consent to their data being stored and processed in this manner. We use these restricted utilisation profiles exclusively for the purpose of being able to offer the function described herein.

      * **dd)**

In addition, our web pages make use of so-called cookies. Cookies are small files stored on your hard disk through which we receive certain information. This information includes, in particular, the IP address, log-in data, user’s type of browser and browser version, e-mail addresses, the URL clickstream (i.e. which pages of our website a user has visited and in what order), date and time of user’s visit and cookie number.

The use of cookies at registration and within the scope of subsequent use of our services enables us initially to recognise the user whenever he revisits our website after an earlier session. For this function to apply, however, a user must select the corresponding option on our websites. Moreover, cookies help us to fine-tune our offer to the individual needs of users in an optimum way.

We also use cookies to gather statistics on the frequency of visits to individual pages of our Internet service, to record general navigation patterns, and, if applicable, to set up pseudonym-based profiles (see above).

For users wishing to block the use of cookies, browsers offer the option of stopping acceptance and storage of cookies. In order to find out how this works for a particular browser, users can call up their browser’s help function or ask the manufacturer. We point out, however, that the cookies function must be switched on for user registration and for subsequent log-ins.

      * **ee)**

Unless the user raises an objection (cf. on this subject below) or blocks the use of cookies through the browser from the outset (cf. preceding paragraph), a so-called DART Cookie of Google Inc., domiciled in Mountain View, CA, U.S.A., will be stored on the user’s browser whenever he visits our website. The purpose of this cookie is to present to the user a type of advertising which corresponds to the user’s interests. There will be no more advertising but rather advertising better targeted on the user.

However, the following is important: The cookie does not result in our or Google Inc.’s receipt and storage of personal data about the user and his personal interests. The cookie rather functions in such a way that when the user visits an Internet page a certain number is stored on the user’s browser, which is allocable to a certain field of interest reflected by the content and subject of the page concerned. When the user visits our website or even a third-party’s website the next time, it will be possible to offer advertising corresponding to the user’s interests rather than random advertising. In this context, neither we nor Google Inc. have any option of drawing conclusions regarding the individual user. The cookie merely imparts the knowledge that a web page is just being visited with a browser whose anonymous user is interested in a particular subject. For additional information concerning the functioning of the cookie please consult <http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/html/intl/de/about.html>.

      * **ff)**

Users may object to the data collection and storage according to sections 2) b) bb) to ee) at any time by e-mail to support@blog.de. As regards the DART Cookie users may, moreover, use the following direct – and simpler – channels:

        * At <http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/index.aspx> users may declare to “opt out” regarding the DART Cookie directly to the manufacturer by clicking the button “AD COOKIE OPT-OUT”. In this case no additional information will be stored and transmitted via the DART Cookie.
        * At [http://www.google.com/privacy ads.html](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html) the user may, moreover, declare to “opt-out” not only with regard to the DART Cookie but also other functions offered by Google Inc.
      * **gg)**

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses so-called cookies, i.e. text files which are stored on your computer and enable an analysis of the use of the website by you. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is usually transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. However, if the IP anonymisation on this website is activated, your IP address will be shortened prior to this by Google within the member states of the European Union or in other contractual states of the Treaty on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. On behalf of the operator of this website, Google will use the information to evaluate your use of the website, compile reports on the website activities and provide other services associated with the website usage and the internet usage to the website operator. The IP address transmitted by your browser in the context of Google Analytics will not be combined with other data of Google. You may prevent storage of the cookies by making appropriate settings in your browser software. However, we point out that in such a case you may not be able to use all the functions of this website to the full extent. Moreover, you may prevent collection of the data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the website (including your IP address) by Google and the processing of that data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available from the following link: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de>.

More detailed information on this is provided at <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de> or at <http://www.google.com/intl/de/analytics/privacyoverview.html> (general information on Google Analytics and data privacy). We point out that on this website Google Analytics has been extended by the code "gat._anonymizeIp();" to guarantee anonymised collection of IP addresses (so-called IP masking).

    * ####  **c)** External Links

Our website may contain links to the websites of third-party providers not connected with Populis GmbH. Once a user has clicked on such a link, we no longer have any influence on the processing of any personal data made available to third parties as a result of clicking the link (for instance the IP address or the URL where the link is located), as the activities of third parties are by their very nature not within our control. We can therefore assume no responsibility for the processing of such personal data by third parties.

  * #### **§3.** Passing on information to third parties

We operate online communities where users can publish information about themselves, their profession, their hobbies, etc. and make this information available to third parties on our website. The nature of this service therefore also includes the publication and thus the “passing on” of personal data.

However, users themselves largely decide what information they wish to convey. Any personal data is therefore provided on a voluntary basis and is intended to allow other users and visitors to the website to get to know the user providing it. We make the data provided or released voluntarily by users available to all other users and to other visitors at the corresponding locations of our website. Moreover, users can determine who should have access to the content placed on the site – anyone or only specific other users.

Beyond this, we pass on users' personal data to third parties only if and in so far as this may be necessary to implement our contractual relationships with users, if we are obligated to do so by law, or in the event that this may be necessary to implement our General Conditions of Business and Use or any other agreements concluded with our users, or to assert our rights and claims. In particular, we are entitled to pass on user data to credit reference agencies as may be necessary for verification of creditworthiness in cases where a user has opted for a fee-based service package.

If a user's personal data needs to be passed on for purposes not specified herein, we shall in every individual case solicit the user's consent. It goes without saying that if a user refuses consent no data will be passed on.

  * #### **§4.** Information, amendments, cancellation, suspension of service

If requested to do so in writing or in any other text format, we shall at any time provide our users with information regarding what personal data we have stored about them. Furthermore, users may at any time have us block or delete the data of their user accounts, and thus whatever personal data we have stored about them. The only data not deleted is information required by us to carry out any outstanding tasks or to assert our rights as well as data we are called upon by law to store for a longer period. No activity is then possible within our services without renewed registration.

  * #### **§5.** Security

We apply technical and organisational security measures to ensure that our users' personal data is protected against loss, incorrect changes and unauthorised access by third parties. In any case, only authorised persons have access to our users' personal data, and this only to the extent necessary within the scope of the purposes described above.
